let questions = [
    {
        num: 1,
        question: "What does JVM stand for?",
        answer: " A. Java Virtual Machine",
        options: [
            " A. Java Virtual Machine",
            " B. Java Virtual Memory",
            " C. Java Visual Model",
            " D. Java Variable Method"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 2,
        question: "Which keyword is used to define a constant in Java?",
        answer:" B . final",
        options: [
            " A . var",
            " B . final",
            " C . static",
            " D . const"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 3,
        question: "What is the superclass of all classes in Java?",
        answer:  " A . Object",

        options: [
            " A . Object",
            " B . Superclass",
            " C . Main",
            " D . Base"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 4,
        question: "What is the correct way to declare a method in Java that doesn't return any value?",
        answer:  " A . void myMethod() ",

        options: [
            " A . void myMethod() ",
            " B . int myMethod()",
            " C . myMethod() void",
            " D . myMethod() int"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 5,
        question: "Which of the following is not a valid identifier in Java?",
        answer: " C . 1myVariable",
        options: [
            " A . my_variable",
            " B . $myVariable",
            " C . 1myVariable",
            " D . _myVariable"
        ]
    },
      {
        num: 6,
          question: "What is the result of 5 + 7 + 'Hello' in Java?",
          answer: " C . 57Hello",
        options: [
            " A . 12Hello",
            " B . 5 + 7Hello",
            " C . 57Hello",
            " D . 12"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 7,
        question: "Which keyword is used to inherit a class in Java?",
        answer: " A . extends",
        options: [
            " A . extends",
            " B . implements",
            " C . inherits",
            " D . extendsClass"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 8,
        question: "What is the size of the int data type in Java?",
        answer: " B . 8 bytes",
        options: [
            " A . 4 bytes",
            " B . 8 bytes",
            " C . 2 bytes",
            " D . Depends on the platform"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 9,
        question: "Which collection class allows you to associate a unique key with a value in Java?",
        answer:" B . HashMap",
        options: [
            " A . ArrayList ",
            " B . HashMap",
            " C . LinkedList",
            " D . TreeSet"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 10,
        question: "Which keyword is used to define a class that cannot be instantiated?",
        answer: " C . abstract",
        options: [
            " A . static",
            " B . final",
            " C . abstract",
            " D . private"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 11,
        question: "Which of the following is used to read input from the console in Java?",
        answer: " C . Scanner",
        options: [
            " A . System.in ",
            " B . Console.read()",
            " C . Scanner",
            " D . BufferedReader"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 12,
        question: "What is the default value of a boolean variable in Java?",
        answer:" B . false",
        options: [
            " A . true",
            " B . false",
            " C . null",
            " D . 0"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 13,
        question: "Which of the following is not a primitive data type in Java?",
        answer:" D . string",
        options: [
            " A . int",
            " B . float",
            " C . char",
            " D . string"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 14,
        question: "What is the primary objective of Java programming language?",
        answer:" A . Platform independence ",
        options: [
            " A . Platform independence ",
            " B . Hardware independence",
            " C . Software independence",
            " D . Language independence"
        ]
    },
    {
        num: 15,
        question: "What will happen if you try to compile and run a Java program without a main method?",
        answer: " C . Program will neither compile nor run",
        options: [
            " A . Program will compile but will not run ",
            " B . Program will run but will not compile",
            " C . Program will neither compile nor run",
            " D . Program will compile and run successfully"
        ]
    },

      {
        num: 16,
        question: "What does the 'final' keyword signify in Java?",
        answer: " D . All of the above",
        options: [
            " A . It signifies that a class cannot be subclassed ",
            " B . It signifies that a method cannot be overridden",
            " C . It signifies that a variable's value cannot be changed",
            " D . All of the above"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 17,
        question: "Which method is invoked when an object is garbage collected in Java?",
        answer:" A . finalize()",
        options: [
            " A . finalize()",
            " B . destroy()",
            " C . collect()",
            " D . garbage()"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 18,
        question: "Which of the following is a marker interface in Java?",
        answer:" D . All of the above",
        options: [
            " A . Serializable",
            " B . Cloneable",
            " C . Comparable",
            " D . All of the above"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 19,
        question: "What is the default value of an instance variable in Java?",
        answer:" D . It depends on the data type",
        options: [
            " A . 0",
            " B . null",
            " C . false",
            " D . It depends on the data type"
        ]
    },

    {
        num: 20,
        question: "Which method is used to read input from the console in Java?",
        answer:" A . readLine()",
        options: [
            " A . readLine()",
            " B . read()",
            " C . readInt()",
            " D . input()"
        ]
    },
      
]